Guide to the Sam Reiss Photographs PHOTOS.021.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Personalities/Portraits., 1930s-1975
  - Fenley, John - Vice-President, International Brotherhood Of Electrical Workers, Local #3, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 260)
  - Finley, Murray H. - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 261)
  - Frankel, Julius (Box 3, Folder 262)
  - Franklin, Barbara (Box 3, Folder 263)
  - Fulford, Fred - United Furniture Workers of America, circa 1967 (Box 3, Folder 264)
  - Greenburg, Jacob - Attorney For The National Association For The Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) In The James Meredith Case. (Box 3, Folder 265)
  - Guinan, Matthew - President, Transit Workers Union of America (Box 3, Folder 266)
  - Hall, Paul - Seafarers International Union (Box 3, Folder 267)
  - Hambel, George - Receives Award, Division #1 M.A.B.S.T.O.N., Oct 1, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 268)
  - Hampton, Lionel (Box 3, Folder 269)
  - Height, Dorothy I. (Box 3, Folder 270)
  - Hillman, Bessie - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (Box 3, Folder 271)
  - Hollander, Louis - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (Box 3, Folder 272)
  - Iaccio, Sal - Vice-President, International Association of Machinists (Box 3, Folder 273)
  - Isaacson, William (Box 4, Folder 274)
  - Iushewitz, Morris (Box 4, Folder 275)
  - Kaufman, Irving (Judge) [Presided Over The Ethel and Julius Rosenberg Case], May 1974 (Box 4, Folder 276)
  - Kaufman, Stephan B. (Councilman - Bronx) (Box 4, Folder 277)
  - Kennedy, Edward (Box 4, Folder 278)
  - Kennedy, John F. - Presidential Campaign (New York City), 1960 [includes Kennedy, other politicians and labor leaders] (Box 4, Folder 279)
  - Kennedy, Robert, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 280)
  - Kerrigan, [First Name?] (Box 4, Folder 281)
  - King, Coretta Scott (Box 4, Folder 282)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr. - At Reception For Him At Commodore Hotel, New York City, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 283)
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr. - Portrait, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 284)
  - Kirkland, Lane (Box 4, Folder 285)
  - Kovenetsky, Sam (Box 4, Folder 286)
  - Kroll, Jack - Director CIO-PAC (Congress of Industrial Organizations--Political Action Committee) (Box 4, Folder 287)
  - Kugler, Israel - Professional Staff Congress, circa 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 288)
  - Lagana, Philip - President, New York State Tax Commission (Box 4, Folder 289)
  - Lapson, Sam - Doll House Furniture Maker (Box 4, Folder 290)
  - Lefkowitz, Louis - New York State Attorney General, 1957-1978 (Box 4, Folder 291)
  - Levine, Larry (Box 4, Folder 292)
  - Levine, Lou - At Sam Kovenetsky Dinner; Portraits; And Various (Box 4, Folder 293)
  - Livingston, David - United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 (Box 4, Folder 294)
  - Malofsky, Solly, May 1974 (Box 4, Folder 295)
  - Maloney, Edgar - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 3 - Receives A Retirement Plaque, Oct 1974 (Box 4, Folder 296)
  - Marino, Frank - 65th Birthday Celebration For Him, Hosted By United Furniture Workers of America, Metropolitan District Council #3, Upholsters and Springmakers Local 76, Nov 6, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 297)
  - Martin, Dr. Annie B. (Box 4, Folder 298)
  - Massa, Casear - Retail, Wholesale, Department Store Workers Union - Retirement, Apr 1975 (Box 4, Folder 299)
  - Meany, George (Box 4, Folder 300)
  - Meany, George - Receives Congressional Medal Of Honor (Box 4, Folder 301)
  - Meir, Golda (Box 4, Folder 302)
  - Mercurio, [First Name?] (Box 4, Folder 303)
  - Miller, Ruth (Box 4, Folder 304)
  - Murray, John B. - President [United Association of?] Plumbers, [Local 1?], May 1975 (Box 4, Folder 305)
  - Nader, Ralph (Box 4, Folder 306)
  - O'Neal, Frederick (Box 4, Folder 307)
  - Ottley, Austin (Box 4, Folder 308)
  - Ottley, Peter (Box 4, Folder 309)
  - Papandrea, Jim, Jul 1974 (Box 4, Folder 310)
  - Pensig, Herbert H. (Esq.) - International Ladies Garment Workers Union, Local 102 - Testimonial Dinner And Award, March 18, 1972, Mar 18, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 311)
  - Perez, Frank - Receives Award From New York City Central Labor Council (Box 4, Folder 312)
  - Perry, Al (Box 4, Folder 313)
  - Politicians - Miscellaneous - Including Bella Abzug; Eldon Clingan; Howard Golden; Hubert Humphrey; Lyndon B. Johnson; John Lindsay; Walter Mondale, Henry Morgenthau; Ogden Reid; Stanley Steingut; Robert F. Wagner Jr.; Gerhard "Soapy" Williams; Harrison A. Williams; Malcolm Wilson. (Box 4, Folder 314)
  - Potofsky, Jacob (Box 4, Folder 315)
  - Potofsky, Jacob S. And Nelson J. Rockefeller (Box 4, Folder 316)
  - Powell, Robert E. - Vice President, Laborers International Union of North America (Box 4, Folder 317)
  - Quill, Michael - Transport Workers Union of America (Box 4, Folder 318)
  - Rabkin, Elias - Amalgamateed Clothing Workers of America (Box 4, Folder 319)
  - Ramos, Lucy (Box 4, Folder 320)
  - Randolph, A. Philip (Box 4, Folder 321)
  - Randolph, A. Philip - 70th Birthday Celebration At Carnegie Hall [Eleanor Roosevelt, Martin Luther King, Jr. Present], 1959 (Box 4, Folder 322)
  - Raskin, Abe (Box 4, Folder 323)
  - Rebaldo, Sebastian - United Optical Workers Union, Local 408 - New York City Board of Education Acknowledgement, September 1971, Sep 1971 (Box 4, Folder 324)
  - Reiter, George (Box 4, Folder 326)
  - Reiss family, Moskowitz and Lupowitz Restaurant celebrities, miscellaneous photos, 1906-1997 (Box 9, Folder 1-23)
  - Reiss, Sam (Box 4, Folder 327)
  - Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Workers Union - Local 338 - Portraits (Box 4, Folder 328)
  - Reuther, Walter (Box 4, Folder 329)
  - Riesel, Victor (Box 4, Folder 325)
  - Rizzo, Leonard - International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers (Box 4, Folder 330)
  - Robinson, Cleveland - United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 (Box 4, Folder 331)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson J. (Box 4, Folder 332)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson J. - New York State Labor For Rockefeller Rally [With Andrew Arcuri, Louis Lefkowitz, Peter Brennan And Other Union Officials] (Box 4, Folder 333)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1940-1960 (Box 4, Folder 334)
  - Rosenblum, Frank - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (Box 4, Folder 335)
  - Rustin, Bayard (Box 4, Folder 336)
  - Ryan, Joe - Transport Workers Union, Apr 1975 (Box 4, Folder 337)
  - Ryan, John (Box 4, Folder 338)
  - Salerno, Joseph - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (Box 4, Folder 339)
  - Saltus, Kermit A. - Receives Certificate From Cornell University Labor College, Bronx, New York (Box 4, Folder 340)
  - Samuels, Margaret D. - Receives New York City Central Labor Council Award, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 341)
  - Scarbrough, Carl - United Furniture Workers, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 342)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., Apr 1974 (Box 4, Folder 343)
  - Shanker, Albert (Box 4, Folder 344)
  - Sheinkman, Jacob - New York City Central Labor Council (Box 4, Folder 345)
  - Sheinman, [First Name?] (Box 4, Folder 346)
  - Siegal, David - President, Dining Room Employees Union, Local 1 (Box 4, Folder 347)
  - Simon, Louis - Amalgamated Laundry Workers (Box 4, Folder 348)
  - Solomon, Jack [Health Food Restauranteur - Ca. 1930's], circa 1930's (Box 4, Folder 349)
  - Speakers - (Mainly Labor) - Unidentified (Box 4, Folder 350)
  - Stearns, Ed (Box 4, Folder 351)
  - Stokowski, Leopold - Portraits; Honored By American Federation of Musicians, Local 802 (Box 4, Folder 352)
  - Swidler, Joseph - Chair, Public Service Commission (Box 4, Folder 353)
  - Thomas, Norman (Box 4, Folder 354)
  - Transport Workers Union - Portraits (Box 4, Folder 355)
  - Trenz, James - Founder, Local 463, International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers (Box 4, Folder 356)
  - U Thant, Pantanow - At Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America Convention - Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 357)
  - United Federation of Teachers - Portraits (Box 4, Folder 358)
  - Van Arsdale, Harry (Box 4, Folder 359)
  - Vishniac, Roman - At Jewish Museum, December 26, 1971, Dec 26, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 360)
  - Watts, Roosevelt (Box 4, Folder 361)
  - Welch, Ed (Box 4, Folder 362)
  - Young, Andrew, Feb 1974 (Box 4, Folder 363)
  - Zimmerman, Charles - International Ladies Garment Workers Union - Receives Morris Hillquit Award, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 364)
- Series V: Labor Education., 1960s-1975
  - Center For Labor Studies Of Empire State College, State University Of New York ("Labor College"), 1970s (Box 4, Folder 365)
  - Cornell University School Of Industrial And Labor Relations, circa 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 366)
  - Cornell University School Of Industrial And Labor Relations - Certificate Awards, circa 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 367)
  - Cornell University School Of Industrial And Labor Relations -Certificate For Health Plan Management, circa 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 368)
  - Cornell University School Of Industrial And Labor Relations -Classroom Photos, circa 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 369)
  - Cornell University School Of Industrial And Labor Relations -Women Unionists Seminar, circa 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 370)
- Series VI: Other Clients., 1960s-1975
  - Allied Educational Foundation [including Arthur Schlesinger, Jr., William F. Buckley, Gerald Ford, Walter Mondale] (Box 5, Folder 371)
  - Allied Educational Foundation - Ramsay Clark (color prints), undated (Box 5, Folder 372)
  - American Arbitration Association, undated (Box 5, Folder 373)
  - American Jewish Committee - George Meany Receives The Democratic Heritage Award, undated (Box 5, Folder 374)
  - Boy Scouts/Cub Scouts, undated (Box 5, Folder 375)
  - Boy Scouts - Boy Power 76, Jun 1976 (Box 5, Folder 376)
  - Boys' Club, undated (Box 5, Folder 377)
  - Boys Town, undated (Box 5, Folder 378)
  - City of Hope - Pilot Medical Center, Mar 1975 (Box 5, Folder 379)
  - Coles Brothers Circus - Joe Coles, undated (Box 5, Folder 380)
  - Consumer Assembly of Greater New York - 3rd Annual Meeting, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 381)
  - Consumer Assembly of Greater New York - 5th Annual Meeting, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 382)
  - European Jewish Congress - Israel Bonds, Al Hellman, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 383)
  - Haym Solomon Home for the Aged, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 384)
  - Israel Golden Age Foundation - Martin Koppel Receives "The Golden Age Award", Jan 24, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 385)
  - Kenbert Lighting International Corporation - Receives Department Of Commerce Presidential "E-Star Award", undated (Box 5, Folder 386)
  - Labor Theater, Inc.: John L. Lewis Play, Apr 11, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 387)
  - Lake Peekskill Youth Group (color), undated (Box 5, Folder 388)
  - Louis Simon Scholarship Fund Dinners, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 389)
  - Loyal League of Yiddish Sons of Erin, Mar 1975 (Box 5, Folder 390)
  - Lubman, Seymour A. (Vice President Purepac Pharmaceutical Company) and Mrs. Lubman (?) (color prints), undated (Box 5, Folder 391)
  - National Association for Justice - Washington DC, Sep 4, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 392)
  - New York State Employees Brotherhood Committee, Inc., undated (Box 5, Folder 393)
  - Police Academy, undated (Box 5, Folder 394)
  - Police Training, undated (Box 5, Folder 395)
  - Product Shots (Box 5, Folder 396)
  - Santiago Iglesias Educational Society, Inc., undated (Box 5, Folder 397)
  - The Guardian Insurance Company Of America, undated (Box 5, Folder 398)
  - Unidentified Clients (color prints), undated (Box 5, Folder 399)
  - Unidentified Clients - Studio Portraits Of Children (Box 5, Folder 400)
  - Unidentified Client - Theater Lighting (Box 5, Folder 401)
  - United Housing Foundation, undated (Box 5, Folder 402)
  - United Jewish Appeal - Dinner Honoring Lou Stein, Apr 1965 (Box 5, Folder 403)
- Series VII: Worksites., 1950s-1970s
  - Collecting Eggs, circa 1960's (Box 5, Folder 404)
  - Construction, circa 1960's (Box 5, Folder 405)
  - Electrical Workers, circa 1960's (Box 5, Folder 406)
  - Garment Workers, circa 1950's-1960's (Box 5, Folder 407)
  - Musicians, Conductors, Engineers At Recording Sessions, Circa 1960's-1970's (Box 5, Folder 408)
  - White Collar Work, circa 1950's-1960's (Box 5, Folder 409)
  - Woman Making Pear Butter; Lititz, Pennsylvania, 1963 (Box Shared Tamiment 200, Folder 5)
  - Working in Rain - Various Occupations, circa 1960's (Box 5, Folder 410)
  - Worksites - Miscellaneous, circa 1960's (Box 5, Folder 411)
- Series VIII: Miscellaneous Topics., 1950s-1975
  - Allied Educational Foundation, 1967-1974, undated (Box 10, Folder 17-26)
  - Art Exhibits - Art and Audiences (Box 5, Folder 412)
  - Black History Celebrations, circa 1970's (Box 5, Folder 413)
  - Bowling (Box 5, Folder 414)
  - Buildings - Institutional Buildings - Interior Shots Documenting Poor Physical Conditions And Hygiene (Box 5, Folder 415)
  - Buildings/Construction (Box 5, Folder 416)
  - Cardiac Center events, 1971, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - Carnegie Hall - Performances, circa 1960's (Box 5, Folder 417)
  - Children - Earth Day, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 418)
  - Children - Elementary School Age [including disabled children] - In School And After-School Programs, circa 1950's-1960's (Box 5, Folder 419)
  - Children - Girl Going To Chicago On Airplane, June 8, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 420)
  - Children - In Art Classes Making Art - Ca. 1950's -1960's, circa 1950's-1960's (Box 5, Folder 421)
  - Children - Pre-School And Kindergarten Age - Mainly In School Settings, circa 1950's-1970's (Box 5, Folder 422)
  - Children -- Unidentified, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 200, Folder 1)
  - Chorus, undated (Box 5, Folder 423)
  - Coop Supermarket (Box 5, Folder 424)
  - Families (Box 5, Folder 425)
  - Fashion Shows (Box 5, Folder 426)
  - Food Fair - Bryant Park, New York City, Apr 1975 (Box 5, Folder 427)
  - Group Shots - Probably Labor Gatherings (Box 5, Folder 428)
  - Group Shots - Small - Unidentified (Folder 1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 429)
  - Group Shots - Small - Unidentified (Folder 2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 430)
  - Group Shots - Small - Unidentified (Folder 3 of 3), undated (Box Shared Tamiment 200, Folder 2)
  - Group Shots - Workers - Unidentified (Box 5, Folder 431)
  - Hospital - Interiors/Exteriors - Ca. 1960's, circa 1960's (Box 5, Folder 432)
  - Housing - Cooperative Apartment Buildings [?] (Box 5, Folder 433)
  - Housing - Electchester Apartments Complex (Box 5, Folder 434)
  - Housing - New York City Tenement Interiors And Exteriors (Bad conditions), circa 1960's (Box 5, Folder 435)
  - Housing - Promotion And Neighborhood Meetings For Unidentified Housing Project In New York City, circa 1960's (Box 5, Folder 436)
  - Industrial Electrical (?) Machinery (Box 5, Folder 437)
  - Labor (?) Forum, undated (Box 5, Folder 438)
  - Labor Leaders and Activists [including Lane Kirkland, Victor Riesel, Victor Gotbaum, Ellis van Riper, Jack Sheinkman and Sol Stettin] Interviewed On New York City Radio And Television Programs (Box 6, Folder 439)
  - Labor Negotiations (Box 6, Folder 440)
  - Medical (Box 6, Folder 441)
  - Medical - Union Members, 1970's (Box 6, Folder 442)
  - New York City - Cityscapes (color) (Box 6, Folder 443)
  - New York City - Cityscapes (includes skylines and bridges) And Nature (Box 6, Folder 444)
  - New York City - Street Scenes, circa 1950's-1970's (Box 6, Folder 445, Box Shared Tamiment 200, Folder 3)
  - Nurses - Graduation Ceremony [?] (Box 6, Folder 446)
  - Outings - Boat Trip Around Manhattan (Box 6, Folder 447)
  - Performances - Audiences (Box 6, Folder 448)
  - Performers /Performances - Singers And Musical Theater And Musicians (including a production of "Wonderful Town") (Box 6, Folder 449)
  - Photo Exhibits, Newspaper Clippings, handbooks and notebooks, large frame negatives, 1935-1996 (Box 10, Folder 1-15)
  - Picnic - Possibly from September 1972 - New York State AFL-CIO, 15th Constitutional Convention, Hotel Concord, Kiamesa Lake (Box 6, Folder 450)
  - Ploughshare Sculpture, Undated (Box 6, Folder 451)
  - Portraits - Men - Unidentified - (Folder 1 of 3), circa 1950's-1970's (Box 6, Folder 452)
  - Portraits - Men - Unidentified - (Folder 2 of 3), circa 1950's-1970's (Box 6, Folder 453)
  - Portraits - Men - Unidentified - (Folder 3 of 3), circa 1950's-1970's (Box 6, Folder 454)
  - Portraits - Musicians - Unidentified (Box 6, Folder 455)
  - Portraits - Women - Unidentified, circa 1960's-1970's (Box 6, Folder 456)
  - Posed Shots At Social Gatherings (Box 6, Folder 457)
  - Puerto Rican Art Exhibit (attended by Herman Badillo, Bayard Rustin, Percy Sutton), circa 1970's (Box 6, Folder 458)
  - Puerto Rican Day Celebration (?) (at a school), circa 1970 (Box 6, Folder 459)
  - Puerto Rico and St. Thomas - Tourist Shots; Street Scenes; Poverty (Box 6, Folder 460)
  - Retirees - Labor Union - Sponsored Activities And Events (Box 6, Folder 461)
  - Scholarships/Awards (Box 6, Folder 462)
  - Schools - Dedication Of Rosa Taylor Weatherless Annex At P.S. 274, Sep 1971 (Box 6, Folder 463)
  - Schools - Elementary Schools - Students And Teachers, circa 1960's-1970's (Box 6, Folder 464)
  - Schools - High Schools (Box 6, Folder 465)
  - Schools - School Building Interior Shots Documenting Damage And Bad Conditions (Box 6, Folder 466)
  - Shufar [Synagogue - Israel?] (Box 6, Folder 467)
  - Social Gatherings / Dinners - Unidentified (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 468)
  - Social Gatherings / Dinners - Unidentified (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 469)
  - Sports And Recreation (Box 6, Folder 470)
  - Swearing In / Taking Oaths (Mostly Labor Unions) (Box 6, Folder 471)
  - Unidentified Trade Show [?], undated (Box 6, Folder 472)
  - Union and Labor Meetings - Unidentified (Folder 1 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 473)
  - Union and Labor Meetings - Unidentified (Folder 2 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 474)
  - Union and Labor Meetings - Unidentified (Folder 3 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 475)
  - Union and Labor Meetings - Unidentified (Folder 4 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 476)
  - United Nations - Visitors To And Construction Of Part Of U.N. Complex, circa 1950's-1960's (Box 6, Folder 477)
  - Voting And Voter Registration (Box 6, Folder 478)
  - World Trade Center Towers - Under Construction, 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 479)
- Series IX: Oversized Prints., 1950s-1970s
  - Oversized black and white photographs (Box Shared Tamiment XOS003, Folder 1, Box 7, Folder 480, Flat-file-folder 3)
  - Oversized color photographs (Box 7, Folder 481)
  - Oversize black and white photographs: 1975 retrospective of Reiss' work, plus Manhattan skyline and World Trade Center construction. (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
  - Oversize loose black and white photographs, 1915-1973 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Rolled photographs are not available to researchers.